Guide to the Miguel A. Gandert Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 2003 Acquisition, 1982-2001; 3; 5.34; (32 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Nuevo México Profundo
      - Unmatted Prints
        - 8 inches by 10 inches
          - Memorias del Cautivo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 56)
          - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 56)
          - El Poder de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 56)
          - Siempre Devoto, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 56)
          - Tierra Sagrada, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 56)
          - Baile Redondo, Llano Quemado, 1997 (Box 56)
          - Las Comanchas y sus Cautivas, Los Griegos, 1997 (Box 56)
          - Tres Generaciones Cantando, Ranchos de Taos, 1997 (Box 56)
          - Tormento de los Toritos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 56)
          - El Espantado, Talpa, 1998 (Box 56)
          - Danza del Aguila, Talpa, 1998 (Box 56)
          - Soldado de la Virgen, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 56)
          - Untitled photographs, 1993-1999, undated; 14 (Box 56)
        - 11 inches by 14 inches
          - Untitled, Tomé, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Sueño del Abuelo, Picurís, 1992 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Dia de la Guadalupano, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Mañanitas del Niño Manuel, Ranchos de Taos, 1995 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Linda Elena, Talpa, 1995 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Panzante, Picurís, 1996 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo, Picurís, 1996 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Capilla de Talpa, Talpa, 1997 (Box 57 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Talpa, 1998 (Box 57 (Oversize))
        - 16 inches by 20 inches
          This group includes a few panoramic photographs. Most prints signed and dated by Gandert on the versos.
          - Despedida, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1986 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Procesión de San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1987 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Feast of San Isidro, Atrisco, 1988; 3 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - La Malinche y su Luz, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Soldados de San Antonio, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Procesión del Señor de Mapimí, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Altar de la Esquina, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1989 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Devoción de Mano Lupe, Tomé, 1989 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Pasos al Calvario, Tomé, 1989; 2 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Sueño del Abuelo, Picurís, 1992; 2 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Hermanos de la Morada, Tomé, 1992 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Trompetas y Clarines, Tomé, 1992 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Escapulario, Tomé, 1992; 2 (Box 58 (Oversize))
          - Edwin y su Tombé, Tomé, 1992; 2 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - El Gobernador, Picurís, 1992 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Malinche y su Abuela, Picurís, 1992 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Ojos al Cielo, Tomé, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Matachines de Noche Buena, Picurís, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Tomé, 1993; 3 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Altar, Tomé, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Recuerdos de Robyn, Tomé, 1993; 2 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Juan Maetas, Tomé, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Siempre la Cruz, Chimayó, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - La Victoria del Rey Alfonso, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 59 (Oversize))
          - Batalla de Moros y Cristianos, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Luminaria, Picurís, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Soldado de la Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Dolor de Abuelo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupano, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Indito de la Sierra, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Charro, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Fe y Orgullo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Danzantes de la Plaza, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Devotos del Cerno, "A" Mountain, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Siempre la Cruz, Chimayó, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Adorando a San Luis Gonzaga, San Luis, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Sombra del Monarca, Picurís, 1994; 2 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo de Cuerno Verde, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Galento el Embajador, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 60 (Oversize))
          - Familia, Nogales, Sonora, México, 1994 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - El Abuelo y su Gente, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Galento el Embajador, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Los Cautivos, Talpa, 1995; 2 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Talpa, 1995; 2 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Tanya Trujillo, Talpa, 1995 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Linda Elena, Talpa, 1995; 2 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Luis Jiron, Talpa, 1995; 2 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Nuestro Señor de Esquipulas, Chimayó, 1995 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo del Matachín, Alcalde, 1995 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - David Gonzales, Talpa, 1995 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Músicos y Santos, Picurís, 1995 (Box 61 (Oversize))
          - Malinche y Abuelo, Picurís, 1995 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Espantado, Talpa, 1995 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Memorias del Cautivo, Talpa, 1996; 2 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Picurís, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Tortugas, 1996; 2 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Las Malinches, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Monarca y su Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Comanchitos de Noche Buena, Bernalillo, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Descanso, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Palabra de Dios, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 62 (Oversize))
          - Música para Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996; 2 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupana del Alma, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Memorias del Cautivo, Talpa, 1996; 2 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Cuerno Verde, Alcalde, 1996; 2 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - La Batalla, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Cumbre de la Cruz, Tomé, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Palabra de Dios, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Tierra Sagrada, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Nevada del Año Nuevo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Abuela, Picurís, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - El Toro, Picurís, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Capilla de Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 63 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Sumiso, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Las Malinches, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Pelea de los Abuelos, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos y Caminos, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Misericordia de Chimayó, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Malinche Tonantzina, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos de la Salud, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Siempre Devoto, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Baile Redondo, Llano Quemado, 1997; 3 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Tragos y Dulces, Talpa, 1997; 2 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Talpa, 1997; 2 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Bendición de las Aguas, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 64 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Feast of San Isidro, Atrisco, 1997; 6 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Tormento de los Toritos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Entrega de San Isidro, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Tres Generaciones Cantando, Ranchos de Taos, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Capilla de Talpa, Talpa, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Tres Músicos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Turkey Clan, Talpa, 1997 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Baile de Espantado, Llano Quemado, 1998 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Ojos al Cielo, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 65 (Oversize))
          - Danza del Aguila, Talpa, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Devoción de los Apaches, Juárez, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Danza en el Nuevo Templo, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Niños y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Javier y su Hijita, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo del Guadalupano, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Bendiciones del Desierto, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Danzante y Malinche, Ranchos de Anapra, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Stations of the Cross, Chimayó, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Atrocidades de la Perijundia, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - Adorando San Antonio, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - San Antonio Matachín, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - La Batalla, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 66 (Oversize))
          - La Fe de los Hijos, Tomé, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos de la Salud, Tomé, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Danza del Monarca, Picurís, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Caído, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Toritos Capados, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Cuerno Verde y Don Carlos Fernández, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Quiotes en la Puerta, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos del Noche, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Balazo del Arzobispo, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Plumas en el Viento, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Danzantes de Plumas, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
            Varient title and date in Nuevo México Profundo: Rituals of an Indo-Hispano Homeland: Matachines de Carrizo, Tortugas, 1993.
          - Devociones Guadalupanas, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Adorando a San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
          - Baile del Borracho, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 67 (Oversize))
        - 20 inches by 24 inches
          - La Malinche y su Luz, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Arco de Triunfo, Bernalillo, 1991 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Hermanos de la Morada, Tomé, 1992 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Trompetas y Clarines, Tomé, 1992 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Cerro de Tomé, Tomé, 1993 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - General Azteca Chichimeca, Tortugas, 1993 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - El Toro Peleando, San Luis, 1993 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Vísperas de la Virgen, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo de Cuerno Verde, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Juan Diego y su Reina, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 68 (Oversize))
          - Mañanitas del Nino Manuel, Ranchos de Taos, New Mexico, 1995 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo del Matachín, Alcalde, 1995 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Alegría de los Matachines, Picurís, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Cuarto de Milagros, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Good Friday, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupana del Alma, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Palabra de Dios, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - Al Pie de la Cruz, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 69 (Oversize))
          - El Poder de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Tierra Sagrada, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - El Toro, Picurís, 1996 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Baile Redondo, Llano Quemado, 1997 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Las Comanchas y sus Cautivas, Los Griegos, 1997 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Entrega de San Isidro, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Tormento de los Toritos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Baile del Espantado, Llano Quemado, 1998 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Soldado de la Virgen, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 70 (Oversize))
          - Floyd y su Tombé, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 70 (Oversize))
      - Color Prints
        This group of material consists of photographic prints, 8 inches by 10 inches.
        - Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 56)
        - Picurís, 1992 (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous Prints
      This group of photographs includes portraits of Hispanic artists, Mexican migrants, prostitutes and depictions of traditional Hispanic farms among others.
      Organized under three headings: Contact Sheets from 35 mm Black-and-White Film, Matted Prints, and Unmatted Prints.
      - Contact Sheets from 35mm Black-and-White Film
        - 1982, 2; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1983, 2; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1986, 5; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1987, 2; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1988, 2; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1989, 1; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1990, 1; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1991, 26; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1992, 12; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1993, 4; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1994, 5; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1995, 11; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1996, 3; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1997, 4; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - 1998, 1; contact sheets (Box 71)
        - Enlargements of contact sheets, 4 (Box 72 (Oversize))
      - Matted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - Lucy Delgado, Mexican Transvestite, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 73 (Oversize))
        - Musician, Callo Benito, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 73 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints
        Organized under four headings by print size: 8.5 inches by 11 inches and smaller, 11 inches by 14 inches and smaller, 16 inches by 20 inches, and 20 inches by 24 inches.
        - 8.5 inches by 11 inches and smaller
          - Persian Gulf Protest, 1991; 3 (Box 74)
          - Lete, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 74)
          - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 74)
          - Henry Roth, 1992 (Box 74)
          - Calvario, Holman, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 74)
          - Chimayó, 1993 (Box 74)
          - Los Chileros, Chimayó, 1993 (Box 74)
          - Juárez, México, 1993; 1; color print (Box 74)
          - Dante Medina, 1994 (Box 74)
          - Barelas, New Mexico, 1994-1995; 2 (Box 74)
          - Pat Mora, 1997; 2 (Box 74)
          - Edward T. Hall, 1997 (Box 74)
          - Talpa, 1997 (Box 74)
          - Falla's, Valencia, Spain, 1999 (Box 74)
          - San José, 2001 (Box 74)
          - Ranchos de Taos, 2001; 2 (Box 74)
          - Trampas de Taos, 2001; 2 (Box 74)
          - Planting Winter Wheat, San Luis, Colorado, undated (Box 74)
          - Bry, undated (Box 74)
          - Charles Carrillo, undated; 2 (Box 74)
          - Untitled photograph, undated (Box 74)
        - 11 inches by 14 inches and smaller
          Photographs include print dates ranging from 1992 to 2003.
          - Lucy and Joel, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Horacio Martinez, Martineztown, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Family, Martineztown, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Española, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 75 (Oversize))
            Also titled "Lowriders" as part of the Reflexiones del Corazón project.
          - Untitled, Juárez, México, 1993; 2 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Pedro Ramierez, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1994 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Nogales, Arizona, 1994; 6 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Gary Sedillo, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1994 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Prostitute, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Street Prostitute, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Tilling the Soil, San Luis, Arizona, 1995 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - Cutting Grass, Rodarte, 1995 (Box 75 (Oversize))
          - San Luis Valley, 1995 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Portrait, Tortugas, New Mexico, 1996 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Morada, Lower Las Colonias, New Mexico, 1996-1997; 2 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Feast of San Isidro, Atrisco, 1997; 3 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Adelmo Kaber Sanches and his son Edwin planting winter wheat, 1997 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Estevan Arellano, Irrigating Milpa, Embado, México, 1998 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Manuel Prut, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1999; 2 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Self-portraits, 1999-2000; 2 (Box 76 (Oversize))
          - Hispano artists, undated; 4 (Box 76 (Oversize))
        - 16 inches by 20 inches
          Most photographs signed and dated by Gandert. This group of material includes ten panoramic prints.
          - Alfalfa Cutting, Rodarte, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Descanso, Pantaeon, Juárez, México, 1988 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Juárez, México, 1988; 2 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Hermano Juan Roybal, Las Colonias de Arriba, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Juarita, Juárez, México, 1989 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Street Prostitute, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - El Puerto, Salon de Baile, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Border Crossing, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Puente Negro, Juárez, México, 1991 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Holman, New Mexico, 1992; 1 panoramic print (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Shovels, La Cueva, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 77 (Oversize))
            Alternate title by Gandert: Shovels for Adobes.
          - Calvario, Holman, New Mexico, 1992; 1 panoramic print (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Chimayó Milpa, Chimayó, New Mexico, 1992; 1 panoramic print (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Morada, Chacon, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 77 (Oversize))
          - Lele, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Danza Azteca, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Photographer, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Lucy and Joel, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Kevin and Mindy, Tommie's, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1993 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Pedro Ramierez, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1993 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Downtown Alba, 1994 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Headgate, Rio Calebra Watershed, San Luis, Colorado, 1995; 1 panoramic print (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Inmate, Prison of New Mexico, Santa Fe, 1994 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - People's Ditch and Oldest Barn in Colorado, Gallegos Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1995; 1 panoramic print (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Sociedad Protección Mutua de Trabajadores Unidos, Chama, Colorado, 1995; 1 panoramic print (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Cutting Hay, San Luis, Colorado, 1995; 1 panoramic print (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Abandoned House, San Luis, Colorado, 1995; 1 panoramic print (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Adelmo Kaber, Potato Cellar, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Old Praxiades Ortega, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Tattoo, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 78 (Oversize))
          - Earth First Protestors, Jaroso Gate Taylor Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Earth First Protester, San Francisco Gate, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Logging Truck, Jaroso Gate Taylor Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Street Preachers, Juárez, México, 1996 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Adelmo Kaber Prepares Land for Planting, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Adelmo Kaber Sanchez and his Son Edwin Sanchez Planting Winter Wheat, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Adelmo Kaber and Veronica Sanchez, Separating Seed from Chaff, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Iglesia de San Acacio, San Acacio, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Mexican Migrants Harvest Peas, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Mexican Migrant Child, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Los Mayordomos de San Isidro, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Congarto Familia, Juárez, México, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Lágrimas, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1997 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Morada, Truchas, New Mexico, 1998 (Box 79 (Oversize))
          - Fallas, Valencia, Spain, 1998 (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Untitled, Valencia, Spain, 1998; 2 (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Waterfall, Acequia de la Presa, Chacon, New Mexico, 1999; 1 panoramic print (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Rodarte, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Acequia Canoe, Trampas, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Mora River, Mora, New Mexico, 1999; 1 panoramic print (Box 80 (Oversize))
          - Cutting Alfalfa, Chacon, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 80 (Oversize))
        - 20 inches by 24 inches
          - Matachine, Albuquerque, New Mexico / Varrio San José, 1986 (Box 81 (Oversize))
          - Peace Protest, Old Town, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1990 (Box 81 (Oversize))
          - Pro-War-Protest, Old Town Plaza, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1990 (Box 81 (Oversize))
          - Teresa Gutiérrez, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 81 (Oversize))
  - Printed Material
    This subseries consists of calendars, magazines, and newspaper clippings with photographic images by Gandert.
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, 1993-2000; 25 folders, including 3 compact discs (Box 82)
      Compact discs are stored in: Restricted Fragile Box 87. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, circa 1987-2001; 47 (Box 83)
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, 1993-2003; 6 (Box 84)
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, 1996-2000; 3 (Box 85)
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, circa 1991-2003 (Box 86)
  - Restricted Fragile Material
    - Tesoros del Espíritu: A Portrait in Sound of Hispanic New Mexico (audiovisual media), 1996; 3 compact dics (Box 87)
      Box 87 (sound recording): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- June 2005 Acquisition, 1983-2003; 4; 1.38; (15 boxes)
  Box 8 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files are available. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The June 2005 Acquisition documents Gandert's projects and exhibitions, 1983-2003, and chiefly consists of matted black-and-white prints, digital files, and printed material.
  - Photographs
    This subseries organized under six headings: Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience; Voces de la Terra; Images of San Ysidro; Desde de Nuevo México and Other Prints; Hermanitos Comanchitos: Indo-Hispano Rituals of Captivity and Redemption; and America 24/7.
    - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, mounted in mats, 22 inches by 28 inches.
      - '51 Chevy, 1986 (Box 88 (Oversize))
      - '59 Chevy, 1986 (Box 88 (Oversize))
      - First Plaza, Downtown Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 88 (Oversize))